Qumber Rizvi

Full Stack Developer

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 4+ years of related experience.

Work History

2019-12 -Current

Team Leader - Full Stack Developer

Jamtech Technologies Pvt Ltd, Lucknow

- Mentored and guided teammates to foster proper completion of assigned duties.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Set up and developed infrastructures to meet specific production requirements.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Coordinated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Boosted network, system and data availability and integrity through preventive maintenance and upgrades.
- Developed functional databases, applications and servers to support websites on back-end.
- Delivered more than 20 projects including more than 5 large scale projects.

2018-12 -2019-11

Associate Developer

StarClinch, New Delhi

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and PHP coding.
- Provided back-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.

Contact

Address

Lucknow, UP 226017

Phone

+91 9695538821

E-mail

qumberrizvi@ymail.com

WWW

https://bold.pro/my/qumber/668

LinkedIn

https://in.linkedin.com /in/smqumberrizvi

WWW

https://stackoverflow.com/users/10625611/qumber

Skills

JavaScript / Typescript Proficiency

Advanced

PHP Proficiency

•••••
Advanced

Laravel Proficiency



Angular Proficiency



React & Next Proficiency



Upper intermediate

- Implemented content management and security resource tutorials to assist end-user training.
- Generated web hosting presence to accommodate specified needs and maintain files on account.
- Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets
- Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems.
- Deployed more than 500 merge requests in 6 months.

2018-03 - Software Developer

ExtraClass, Gurugram

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Integrated constructive programs into cohesive product.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments.
- Deployed more than 500 merge requests in 6 months

Projects

2018-12

Rigmeds

https://rigmeds.com

Duration - December 2021 - Present **Technologies used** - Next.js, Laravel, Typescript, PHP,

OneSignal, SES, S3, EC2, CloudFront, CircleCl,

RazorPay

Rigmeds is an e-pharmacy for all of your healthcare

Node / Nest Proficiency

Advanced

ORMs - TypeORM, Eloquent and Django ORM

Advanced

Docker

••••

Upper intermediate

Git

Advanced

Linux / Bash

Advanced

Python proficiency

AWS - EC2, ECS, RDS, S3, SES, SNS, CloudWatch, Route53, IAM, etc.

Upper intermediate

GCP - Compute Cloud, Firebase, Firestore, IAM, etc.

Upper intermediate

Servers: Nginx, Apache

●●●●

Advanced

CI / CD - CircleCI, GitHub Actions, Bitbucket Pipelines

Upper intermediate

Django, Django Rest Framework, Django ORM

Intermediate

Databases - MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, needs. With Rigmeds, you can buy prescription drugs and other healthcare items and have them delivered right to your door. Other features of Rigmeds include consulting doctors and facilitating lab tests.

Tutosh

https://tutosh.com

Duration - January 2021 - Present

Technologies used - Technologies used: Angular, NestJs, Typescript, GraphQL, TypeORM, Redis, Docker, Firebase, Stripe, Paypal, GPay, Socket.io, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, AWS

Tutosh is an online learning platform for tutors and students. Major features of Tutosh include live streamed videos, subject specific classes, live whiteboards, personalised calendars, groups, social networking, live chats, and more.

Hubble Space Telescope Skymap

https://www.nasa.gov/content/exploreour-universe-skymap

Duration - June 2020 - July 2021

Technologies used - React, Redux, D3, Leap Hand Motion Controller, D3 Tiles, JSON Docs, GitHub Pages, GitHub Actions

Skymap shows you all the known clusters, quasars, nebulas, galaxies, supernovas, and other bodies captured by Hubble Space Telescope visually mapped with actual coordinates and scalability.

PebbleKraft

https://www.pebblekraft.com/

Duration - December 2019 - March 2020

Technologies used - Angular, PHP (Lumen), PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, JSON Web Tokens, Redis, Socket.io, S3, ECS, Docker, ELK Stack

PebbleKraft lets stone-crafters sell their products and the consumers to find and purchase the same. PebbleKraft's main mission is to make buying and selling easy for stone and its related products **Firestore**

●●●●Upper intermediate

Languages

English

Advanced

Hindi

••••• Advanced

Urdu

Advanced

Spanish



between builders, manufacturers, distributors, and quarries on a global scale.

Adverto Customer Experience Platform

Duration - August 2020 - Present

Technologies used - Python - Django, Django Rest Framework, Natural Language Toolkit, Matplotlib; MongoDB; JS - React, Redux, Axios, React Router; D3, AWS - EC2, S3, RDS, SES, SNS; Elastic Search, SurveyMonkey APIs

Adverto is a Customer Experience (CX) platform that helps companies boost their businesses using technologies like Natural Language Processing and Data Plotting to provide key information like promoters, passives, detractors, revenue impact, benchmarking, etc.

StarClinch

https://starclinch.com

Duration - May 2019 - Sep 2019

Technologies used - Python (Django), MariaDB, Firestore, Airtable, Integromat; Earlier: WordPress, WooCommerce API, PHP (Laravel), MariaDB, Bootstrap, AJAX, JQuery

StarClinch lets event organisers, event managers, and individuals book artists & celebrities directly through its portal.

Be Humanly

https://behuman.ly

Duration - January 2020 - May 2020 **Technologies used** - Vue, PHP (Laravel), Nginx, EC2, RDS, S3

Be Humanly provides flexible office space and access to a vibrant community of independent health and wellness professionals who value autonomy and ownership.

Leffit CRM

Duration - February 2020 - May 2020

Technologies used: Vue, PHP (Laravel), LaravelExcel,

JWT, Nginx, EC2, RDS, S3

Leffit is a CRM that caters to specific needs of education professionals.

Ramon

Duration - October 2020 - December 2020 **Technologies used** - PHP (Laravel), MariaDB, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Geolocation API, OAuth, GCP - Compute Engine, VPC Firewall

Ramon uses Geolocation APIs to search professionals nearby for a specific category. It also provides Analytics data to its professionals to help them boost their businesses.

Curlen Digital NPI

Duration - May 2020 - August 2020 **Technologies used** - PHP (Laravel), LaravelExcel, MongoDB, Elasticsearch

Curlen Digital NPI lets you look up National Provider Identifier Database which contains over 100 million records of medical professionals and organisations.

ZeroDocs

https://zerodocs.com **Duration** - May 2020 - August 2020 **Technologies used** - PHP (Laravel), MariaDB, Bootstrap, JavaScript

ZeroDocs helps create specifications for design professionals and building product manufacturers.

Education

2015-07 - Bachelor of Computer Applications: Computer Engineering

Shri Ramswaroop Memorial University - Lucknow, India

2013-06 - Intermediate College: Physics And

2015-06	Chemistry
	Indian School Certificate - New Delhi, India
2010-06 -	High School: Mathematics And Science
2012-06	Indian Certificate of Secondary Education - New Delhi, India

Interests

IoT - Tinkering with Arduino and sensors to make magic

Reading, writing, poetry writing, and traveling

Learning new languages - ¿Donde esta la biblioteca?

Learning instruments - currently violin

Distro hopping - I use Arch, btw.